heraldnet.com 2015-12-07

# Legal information | HeraldNet.com - Everett and Snohomish County, Washington

## Copyright and Privacy policy

The Daily Herald Co. is committed to online privacy and respecting the rights of its Web site users. The following information discloses: the information gathering and dissemination practices for all Daily Herald Co. Web sites; copyright policy; and conditions of use. 

By visiting any Daily Herald Co. Web site and using its services, you agree to be bound by the conditions and policies of the site. You represent you have read in entirety and agree to abide by the conditions on this page and recognize the privacy policies contained herein.

## Copyright

**Copyright ©1996-2020.**  
The Daily Herald Co.  
ALL RIGHTS RESERVED.

All Web site pages, design, text, photographs, graphics, and the selection and arrangement thereof Copyright ©1996-2020, The Daily Herald Co., ALL RIGHTS RESERVED.

This service (including, but not limited to text, photographs, graphics, video and audio content) is protected by copyright as a collective work or compilation under the copyright laws of the United States. 

Except for content you have posted on HeraldNet, you may not copy, reproduce, distribute, publish, enter into a database, display, perform, modify, create derivative works, transmit, or in any way exploit any part of this service for your own personal use. You may make one machine readable copy and/or one print copy that is limited to occasional articles of personal interest only. Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, you may not distribute any part of HeraldNet over any network, including a local area network, nor sell or offer it for sale. In addition, these files may not be used to construct any kind of database. 

Any use of materials on this Web site -- including reproduction for purposes other than that noted above, modification, distribution, or republication -- without the prior written permission of The Daily Herald Co. is strictly prohibited.

**Limited license**  
Visitors to HeraldNet are granted a limited license to access the content contained within the HeraldNet site, but are excluded from framing of or deep linking to any pages, articles, photos, or other content on HeraldNet without prior permission. For information on how to request permission to link, please visit our [link request page](http://www.heraldnet.com/linktous/).

**Associated Press**  
Associated Press text, photo, graphic, audio and/or video material shall not be published, broadcast, rewritten for broadcast or publication or redistributed directly or indirectly in any medium. Neither these AP materials nor any portion thereof may be stored in a computer except for personal and noncommercial use. The AP will not be held liable for any delays, inaccuracies, errors or omissions therefrom or in the transmission or delivery of all or any part thereof or for any damages arising from any of the foregoing.

**Trademarks**  
HERALD, THE HERALD, HERALDNET and ONE CALL CLASSIFIEDS are service marks of The Daily Herald Co. All other trademarks, product names and company names or logos cited herein are the property of their respective owners. 

## Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy** This site does not collect personally identifying information about individuals except when specifically and knowingly provided by such individuals. The occasions of this collection are limited to a visitor using a feedback form, the "E-mail This Story" feature, in submitting a URL for the Web Directory, submitting a classified ad, subscribing to various email lists, digital subscriptions, or subscribing to The Herald printed newspaper. Keyboard input from the user is necessary in all cases.

**What we do with the information** Specific information, such as names and e-mail addresses, provided by users in feedback forms and to e-mail news stories is used internally by The Daily Herald Co. and is never sold nor disclosed to a third party. Any information submitted and posted on the Web site is always at the user's request.

This Web site also collects some involuntary, nonidentifying information about its visitors. We record your IP address - a numeric identification assigned to your computer by your ISP (Internet Service Provider, such as, Earthlink, MSN, or AOL) - to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer our Web site, and to help us identify whether you are a unique or repeat user to the site. Your IP address does not personally identify you to us. Only your ISP contains information about you and a record of when the IP address was assigned to your computer.

**Cookies** Cookies are small text files saved onto your computer's hard drive in a special location that is managed by the web browser. Browser security limitations prevent us from storing large amounts of information and the user is under complete control of the temporary cookie files at all times. Refer to your browser's help documentation for more information on how to manage the cookie files. We use the cookie information to remember who you are when you return and to store information that you may have temporarily saved while visiting the Web site. Cookies are useful when it comes to sites that offer some type of customization. Information is saved in the cookie file, so that when you return to the Web site, your customizations remain. We don't store any personally identifiable information in the cookie file -- only information that can be read by our computer system.

Cookies also help us track the number of repeat visitors to the Web site. A log file is generated each day recording the usage of the Web site, and if a specific cookie is present, noting a return visitor.

**Third Party Advertising** We may use a third-party advertising company to serve ads when you visit our Web site or receive our newsletters. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements on this site and other sites about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please click here. In the course of serving advertisements to you, a third-party advertiser may save their cookie files on your computer.

**Feedback forms** Information collected from the feedback form is used either internally (if the user is submitting feedback about the site) or posted on the Web site (if the user is commenting on a news story on the site). We do not share any personal information with any third parties nor is it used for any other purpose.

**Children under 13** The Daily Herald Co. does not specifically offer any content or features aimed at children under 13. We respectfully ask kids under 13: Do not send any information about yourself to us - including your name, address, or e-mail address. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. In the event that we learn that we have collected any personal information from a child under the age of 13 without verification or parental consent, we will delete that information from our database as quickly as possible. Any parent who has concerns about their children's use of the Web site should contact the Daily Herald Co.

**External Links** This site contains links to other sites, especially in the Web Directory, but also in news stories and throughout the site. The Web site is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of external Web sites, even those with whom The Daily Herald Co. has established special advertising relationships.

**Special Relationships** The Daily Herald CO. has special relationships with other companies to provide specific content. Many of these sites automatically display the "Herald," "HeraldNet" or "Everett Herald" name at the top of the page. The Daily Herald Co. is not responsible for the privacy policies of these third-party affiliates which provide the content for such pages such as Introductions, Zap2it's movie and TV times, Washington State Department of Transportation's traffic cameras, HomeSearch, or Creators Syndicate's Crossword puzzles.

From time to time, certain links to information will appear near or within the classified ads. An example is a mortgage or car payment calculator. The Daily Herald Co. is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

**Limitation of Liability** This service is available "as is." We do not warrant that this service will be uninterrupted or error-free. There may be delays, omissions, interruptions and inaccuracies in the news, information or other materials available through this Web site. We are not responsible for the availability or content of other services that may be linked to this Web site. We reserve the right to correct any errors or omissions in this service. Although we intend to take reasonable steps to prevent the introduction of viruses, worms, "Trojan horses," or other destructive materials to this service, we do not guarantee or warrant that the materials that may be downloaded from this service do not contain such destructive features.

**Security** This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control.

**Applicable law** By visiting this Web site, you agree to that the laws of Snohomish County and the state of Washington, without regard to principles of conflict of laws, will govern these Conditions of Use and this Privacy Policy and any dispute of any sort that might arise between you and The Daily Herald Co. or its affiliates.

**E-mail policy** The Daily Herald complies fully with the federal CAN-SPAM Act of 2003. We will not share, sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your e-mail address for commercial purposes without your permission. If you feel you have received an e-mail from us in error, please contact [webfeedback@heraldnet.com](mailto:webfeedback@heraldnet.com).

**Account and Service-Related E-Mail.** The Daily Herald reserves the right to send you e-mail relating to your account status. This includes order confirmations, renewal/expiration notices, notices of credit-card problems, other transactional e-mails and notifications about major changes to services and/or to our privacy policy. If you have registered for online discussions or other services, you may receive e-mail specific to your participation in those activities.

**E-Mail Newsletters.** The Herald offers several e-mail newsletters. If you no longer wish to receive a specific newsletter, follow the "unsubscribe" instructions located near the bottom of each newsletter.

**Promotional E-Mail.** The Herald may periodically e-mail you messages about products and services that we think may be of interest to you. You can choose not to receive messages in the future by following the "unsubscribe" instructions located near the bottom of each e-mail.

From time to time, The Herald may obtain e-mail addresses from third party sources to be used for promotional e-mails. You can choose not to receive messages in the future by either (1) following the "unsubscribe" instructions located near the bottom of each e-mail.

**Survey E-Mail.** We may send you an e-mail inviting you to participate in user surveys, asking for feedback on HeraldNet.com and existing or prospective products and services, as well as information to better understand our users. User surveys greatly help us to improve our services, and any information we obtain in such surveys will not be shared with third parties, except in aggregate form.

**HTML E-Mail.** When you sign up to receive e-mail from us, you may receive it in HTML (with images) format. If you receive the HTML format, we may place a one-pixel gif to determine whether or not readers viewed the e-mail. This process does not leave any information on your computer, nor does it collect information from your computer. The Herald may share this data with others in aggregate only.

**E-Mails From You.** If you send us e-mails, you should be aware that information disclosed in e-mails may not be secure or encrypted and thus may be available to others. We suggest that you exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal or confidential information in e-mails. We will use your e-mail address to respond directly to your questions or comments.

**E-Mail This Article Feature.** HeraldNet.com readers may use this feature to e-mail links to articles (or other content such as slideshows). The e-mail addresses that you supply to this service are saved for your convenience for future articles you may wish to e-mail; these addresses are not used for any other purpose, and will not be shared with any third parties.

**Opting Out of E-Mail Promotions** If, at any time, you prefer not to receive e-mail marketing information from us, simply follow the unsubscribe options at the bottom of each e-mail, to manage your e-mail subscriptions from HeraldNet.com. These include Today's Headlines, Ticketwatch, DealBook, Sophisticated Shopper, Movies Update, etc.

If you experience difficulty with the unsubscribe process, feel free to contact us at [webfeedback@heraldnet.com](mailto:webfeedback@heraldnet.com) and provide your e-mail address along with the name of the newsletter from which you would like to unsubscribe.

**Is my information protected?** To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place commercially reasonable physical, technical and administrative controls to protect the information. Please note that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure.

**Compliance With Legal Process** We may disclose personal information if we are required to do so by law or we have a good faith belief that such action is necessary to (1) comply with the law or with legal process; (2) protect and defend our rights and property; (3) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of The Herald's services; or (4) protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public (among other things, this means that if you provide false information or attempt to pose as someone else, information about you may be disclosed as part of any investigation into your actions).

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact:   
**The Daily Herald Co.**  
PO Box 930  
Everett, WA 98206  
425-339-3433
